In this exercise, you were asked to implement a function
that calculates the intersection of a union between two bounding boxes.
Both bounding boxes were defined by four coordinates.
Two, for the upper left corner and two for the lower right corner of the bounding box.
First, we need to calculate the coordinates of
the bounding box created by the intersection of these two bounding boxes.
We need to keep in mind that these bounding boxes may not intersect,
and this is why I am using the max function here.
Then to calculate the union,
we need to first calculate the area of both input bounding boxes.
Finally, when calculating the union,
we should not forget to subtract the area of the intersection.
This function is very useful and we will be reusing it in further exercises.
In the second part of this exercise,
you were asked to implement a function that calculates precision and
recall for a list of predicted and ground truth bounding boxes.
We can use the numpy.where function to
find where bounding boxes are intersecting with an iou over 0.5.
We can then loop over the values and
compare the ground truth classes with the predicted classes.
If they are equal,
we have a true positive.
But if they are not equal,
we have a false-positive.
To calculate the false negatives,
we first get the number of ground truth
bounding boxes that have not been matched with any predicted bounding boxes.
The false negative are calculated by subtracting
this number to the total number of ground truth bounding boxes.
Finally, we use the formula learned in the lesson to calculate precision and recall.